-Sara Coren - Web Developer

PROFILE

I am a product driven front-end web developer excited about expanding my knowledge base in the field. I have had a variety of experiences with web development, user experience design, quality assurance testing and analytics. I am passionate about using my web development skills and human centered approach to design to help people around the world access information and improve the quality of their lives.

CONTACT

610.772.1279

sara.coren@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/saracoren

https://github.com/saracoren

https://saracoren.github.io/ Portfolio/

SKILLS

WordPress, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, APIs, Mongo, Materialize, Bootstrap, Heroku, PHP, SQL, React, Git/ GitHub, Bitbucket, HubSpot, Litmus, BrowserStack, Photoshop, Adobe XD, Gulp, Sass, MAMP

EDUCATION

Certificate of Completion, Software Engineering General Assembly

Masters in General and Special Education (Gr. 1-6) Touro College

Masters in Geography and Environmental Science University College London

Bachelors in Geology with a Minor in Sociology The College of William & Mary

INTERESTS

UX Design, Innovation, Traveling, Hiking, Kayaking, Volunteering, Cross-Stitching

EXPERIENCE

The Experience Design Studio | Experience Analyst & Developer

August 2020 - Present

Ambler, Pennsylvania / Remote

- Lead Quality Assurance efforts to produce the highest quality products for dozens of different clients in a face-paced agency environment
- Code custom responsive emails and use Litmus to ensure emails are cross client compatible and use HubSpot to manage files and templates and track campaigns
- Code custom WordPress themes using Advanced Custom Fields
- Utilize BrowserStack to test websites across browsers and devices
- Contribute to Bitbucket repositories for version control
- Implement meta data aligned with best SEO practices
- Create tags, triggers and variables in Google Tag Manager for advanced tracking

Center Centre-UIE | Web Developer Intern

January 2020 - August 2020 North Andover, Massachusetts / Remote

- Created a Pattern and Style Library and updated code across all websites
- Updated custom WordPress themes using Gulp, Sass, and MAMP
- Managed and updated content on our various development and live sites using Git
- Coded responsive HTML emails, wrote custom CSS, and scheduled email campaigns
- Utilized WordPress, Statamic and ExpressionEngine CMSs to publish content
- Wrote extensive documentation in Notion for future interns to reference

answerYES Consulting | Web Developer Intern

June 2019 - January 2020

Stamford, Connecticut

- Worked with a small team to redesign and redevelop a WordPress website for a nonprofit organization helping underserved kids in the Bridgeport community
- Gained experience with information architecture, site mapping, writing a custom child theme, working with WP plugins, Photoshop, Adobe XD, and Dreamweaver

Signature Brand Factory | Web Developer Intern

October 2019 - December 2019 Southington, Connecticut

- Customized code on several different WordPress websites using the Divi theme
- Used Photoshop to optimize photos for web development

NYC and CT Schools | Lead Teacher, Grades 2, 3 & 4

August 2010 - June 2018

New York City & Connecticut

- Instructed classrooms of up to 30 students across all subject areas
- Wrote original curriculum and developed project based lessons and activities to help students connect their learning to the real world
- Worked in a small coaching group with Columbia Teachers College staff developers
- Served as president of the School Leadership Team, gave professional development presentations to staff, and trained several student teachers